

GARRETT C. MILLAR

UX/HCI RESEARCHER

CONTACT



RALEIGH, NC



GCMILLAR.GITHUB.IO



GCMILLAR@NCSU.EDU



(336) 202-5732

SKILLS

UX RESEARCH & DESIGN

HCI RESEARCH METHODS

JAVASCRIPT

PYTHON

GIS

STATISTICS

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

DATA VISUALIZATION

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE

COURSES

HUMAN FACTORS METHODS

STATISTICS I, II, III

ERGONOMIC PERFORMANCE ASSESSMENT

COGNITIVE PROCESSES
PHYSIOLOGICAL PSYCHOLOGY
COGNITIVE SCIENCE

PROFILE



A collaborator and researcher with a passion for innovation across a wide variety of platforms. With an inquisitive and empathetic nature, and a background in psychology, computer science, and graphic design, I seek to understand and communicate the human needs, behaviors, motivations, and the physical and cognitive factors that impact the design and function of things. With 8 years in UX / HCI research and design, human computer interaction, computer science, and design strategy, I bring a strong strategic mindset that connects science and art with a core value of user-centered design.

EDUCATION



2018 — 2021 | DOCTORATE OF PHILOSOPHY a,*

Geospatial Analytics

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

2016 — 2018 | DOCTORATE OF PHILOSOPHY

Psychology — Human Factors & Applied Cognition North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

2012 - 2016 | BACHELOR OF ARTS

Psychology

North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC

WORK EXPERIENCE



2021 — PRESENT | USER EXPERIENCE RESEARCHER

LENOVO — MORRISVILLE, NORTH CAROLINA, UNITED STATES

- Lead and conduct UX research across a wide range of website UIs, customer types, and product information.
- Perform competitive analysis, benchmarking, contextual inquiry and other advanced types of usability tests.

2017 — PRESENT | GRADUATE RESEARCH & TEACHING ASSISTANT

CENTER FOR GEOSPATIAL ANALYTICS — NC STATE UNIVERSITY

- Develop, plan, and manage participatory workshops to understand and resolve user needs encountered during the use of web-mapping platforms.
- Design and develop visual tools and features for new GUI and startup-screen to enable intuitive software use for all user levels.

2016 — 2017 | GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

LABORATORY FOR THE STUDY OF METACOGNITION & ADVANCED LEARNING TECHNOLOGIES — NC STATE UNIVERSITY

 Designed, developed, and tested intelligent tutoring systems with virtual agents to promote college students' STEM learning.

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS



- Millar, G. C., Mitas, O., Boode, W., Hoeke, L., de Kruijf, J., Petrasova, A., & Mitasova, H. (2021). Space-time analytics of human physiology for urban planning. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 85, 101554.
- Millar, G. C., Tabrizian P., Petrasova A., Petras V., Harmon B., Mitasova H., Meetenmeyer R. K. (2018). Tangible landscape: A hands-on method for teaching terrain analysis. In Proceedings of the 2018 chi conference on human factors in computing systems (pp. 380:1–380:12). New York, NY, USA: ACM. [Winner of the Honorable Mention for Best Paper Award].
- Pryor, M., Millar, G. C., McNamara, A., Kaufman, L., & McLaughlin, A. C. (2017, September). Creating content guidelines for consistent display of information on an ecommerce website. In Proceedings of the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting (Vol. 61, No. 1, pp. 1834-1838). Sage CA: Los Angeles, CA: SAGE Publications.

a,*Expected defense Fall 2021.